Hope Shines in the Darkest Places
The Cave is a documentary film directed by Feras Fayyad.
Deep beneath the surface in the Syrian province of Ghouta, a group of
female doctors have established an underground field hospital.
Under the supervision of paediatrician Dr.
Amani and her staff of doctors and nurses, hope is restored for some of the thousands
of children and civilian victims of the ruthless Syrian civil war.
Herself, played by Amani Ballour.
Himself, played by Salim Namour.
The Cave (Arabic: الكهف) is a 2019 Syrian-Danish documentary film directed
by Feras Fayyad and written by Fayyad and Alisar Hasan.
A companion piece to his earlier film Last Men in Aleppo, the film profiles Dr.
Amani Ballour, a physician in Ghouta who is operating a makeshift
hospital nicknamed "the Cave" during the Syrian Civil War.
The film premiered at the Toronto International Film
Festival (TIFF) on September 5, 2019.
The film explores themes of peace, conflict, human rights.
The tone is thought_provoking.